# Ahmed Komsan

V	Cairo-Egypt
	+201116227207
abla	ahmedkomsan0@gmail.com
ir	www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed-komsan
<b>E</b>	github.com/Ahmed-Komsan

Passionate IOS software engineer with 4 years of IOS development experience using objective-c and swift. I am constantly striving to learn new technologies and look to ways to better myself in this rapidly changing industry. I like to keep things simple, stay agile and responsive, so I can meet requirements quickly.

### **Skills**

- Swift, Objective-C , C/C++
- Xcode, Eclipse, Android Studio
- Jira, Redmine, Confluence
- Zeplin, inVision, Adobe

- Source control : SVN , Git
- Parallel programming in C and MPI
- SQLite, Realm, Core Data and GRDB database

# **Experience**

9/2020 - PRESENT

## Senior IOS Developer / Fawry, Cairo, Egypt

- Collaborated with a team to define, design, and ship new features in both Objective-c and Swift.
- Working on consumer facing apps in mobile payment and digital wallets.
- myFawry app: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/myfawry/id1462911630

9/2018 - 8/2020

## **IOS Developer /** TruDoc 24x7, Cairo, Egypt

- Refactor most of the codes with Swift and MVVM design pattern from Objective-C and MVC.
- Setting up continuous integration and deployment with Fastlane and CircleCi
- Improve Applications security with Code Obfuscation, SSL certificate pinning and others.
- Working extensively with Core Bluetooth framework for communication with IOT medical devices.
- UI implementation programmatically using Constraints and Masonry (SnapKit)
- Worked on Skype for business and TokBox SDK for video calls and POC for Quickblox SDK for messaging
- Working with Git, SourceTree and GitFlow branching model
- TruDoc 24x7 app: https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/trudoc-24x7/id1015588412?mt=8
- AXA OneHealth app: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/axa-onehealth/id1510038887

## IOS Developer / BlaBlaConnect, SygmaTel, Cairo, Egypt

- Worked on hybrid IOS Chatting app (objective-c and swift) and developed from scratch with a team
  of 3 developer a payment app for money transfer in swift.
- UI design implementation using both Storyboards and NIB files
- Implemented Message queuing using RabbitMQ to receive messages from back end servers
- Worked on chatting based on XMPP, receiving and handling XML Packets from ejabberd server
- Worked on VOIP calls based on WebRTC and CallKit
- Implemented End to End Encryption to the chat messages Using PGP Algorithms
- Integrated MangoPay payment gateway
- BlaBlaConnect app: https://itunes.apple.com/eg/app/blabla-connect/id722557476?mt=8

#### **Education**

[2012 - 2015]

## Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science / Faculty of

Computers and Information – Cairo University

- Graduated in 2015 with cumulative GPA of 3.08 / 4
- Major Department: Information Technology
- Minor Department: Computer Science

### **Activities**

- Participated in InnovEgypt and Intel Ideation Camp Program Held in Ain Shams University From 7th to 12th of September 2013.
- Participated in ACM Egyptian Collegiate Programming Contest 2014.
- Participated in IEEEXtreme Programming Competition 8.0 and Ranked 9th in Egypt, 249 out of 1853 team worldwide.
- IEEEXtreme 9.0 Programming Competition Ambassador.

# Languages

- Arabic
- English